[Music]
hello and welcome to episode 9.5 of the
inventory tutorial series i'm actually
recording this from way in the future
i've already filmed quite a lot of extra
stuff i think episode 11 is currently
out but i'm just going to slot this in
between because i've had a question from
watcher on the discord which if you want
to join the discord there's a link in
the description below and they were
asking how when you go over to a chest
and you pressed e it'd bring up the
chest but then if you press b it'd bring
up the same panel so you couldn't for
your player inventory so you couldn't
put things from your actual inventory
into the chest
but by the end of this video we'll fix
that so we can have our inventory panel
up here this is our player inventory so
you can see we can walk away from the
chest this is our backpack with our
hotbar down here and if we go over here
and press e we can then bring up our
backpack put some potions in there
split them put them back in our
inventory split them put them in our
backpack and walk away
come back over press e
and we've got our chest and our backpack
and it's all separate so let's just jump
straight into this quick little fix
video okay so there's a bit of a glaring
issue with uh the inventory project
which i haven't got around to fixing yet
um but it should be quite a simple fix
so you can see here we've got our
backpack if we press b
it uses the dynamic inventory um panel
so we can put stuff in our backpack
instead of on our hot bar
but if we go over to um this chest and
we open up the chest
and then we open up our backpack with
the b button
because it uses the same panel so we
can't put stuff from our backpack into a
chest we'd have to put it on our hot bar
then use the chest
and then put it into the chest which
obviously is
rubbish we don't we don't want it to do
that so let's just quickly fix that and
it's quite a simple fix what we're going
to do is we're going to drag our canvas
and
we're going to expand our canvas
go to our inventory ui controller and
we've got our dynamic inventory pack
here and i'm just going to shut the shop
ui controller you can see you've got the
dynamic inventory um display we've also
got this player backpack i don't know
when
i made this so let's just assume you
don't have that and let's start fresh so
i'm just going to open up this prefab
and delete the player backpack and we'll
go back to our canvas here so we've got
our dynamic inventory panel
i'm going to control d and duplicate
this and then just move this over to
this side and let's rename this to
player inventory and panel so we've got
our dynamic inventory display here and
i'm going to go over to our inventory ui
controller so it seems i started to set
this player backpack panel and at some
point i know maybe i didn't cover it but
that's no biggie um
if i do cover it in a later video just
get past that bit okay so you can see
i've already tried to do this here so
um we've got a public dynamic inventory
display player backpack panel and that's
on our inventory ui controller so let's
just drag our player imagery panel over
to the player backpack panel and we can
also see that in update we've got a
keyboard current key.escape key was
pressed this frame and if the player
backpack panel is open we'll just close
it and then here we've got our inventory
holder um on dynamic inventory display
requested this is what's opening up the
chest panel and it's also opening up the
um
player panel as well so instead of doing
that let's
um i'm just going to duplicate this
method so we'll just control c
control v
and let's name this to display
layer
inventory and then on our player
inventory holder script so we've got
player inventory holder
we've got here if keyboard dot current b
key was pressed this flame
frame on dynamic imagery display
requested and then we're just going to
invoke our primary imagery system and
pass in the offset
what i'm going to do
um see the version i'm working with here
is from episode 11 of the backpack
series if you're jumping ahead to this
one from episode nine i'm not sure i
can't remember exactly when i
implemented this offset it may have been
in a later video but i'm responding to a
question on discord asking how we can do
this um
i'm going to slot this kind of in
between episode 9 and 11 so this will be
like episode 9.5 as it were so yeah we
should so you should be able to follow
along but there may just be some code
that's not you may see some code that's
not kind of there yet but it will be by
episode 11.
um so we've got if keyboard dot current
b key was pressed this frame and we've
got this event here what i'm actually
going to do is i'm going to create a new
um public static unity action and just
like on our inventory holder this on
dynamic inventory display requested just
to make it easy i'm just going to copy
that i'm going to go back to our player
inventory holder and let's just paste
that in
and then we'll say on player
inventory display requested so now when
the b key is pressed instead of
doing on dynamic inventory display
requested we can say on player inventory
display requested and if it is let's
invoke it and pass in our inventory
system along with the offset again
depending when you're watching this
video you may have your backpack
inventory system as a separate inventory
system
i do rework it to just have one kind of
system but hopefully you can follow
along
we go back to our inventory controller
we just need to listen here so we can do
player inventory holder dot on player
inventory display requested
and then we can plus equals the display
player inventory
and we'll copy this and place it in our
on disable function so we've got our
display player inventory system we're
going to call this so now we just need
to set
our player backpack panel
to true and then we want to refresh the
dynamic inventory of the player backpack
panel not the inventory panel
now if we press play and we press b
that'll bring up our bag
press escape and close that
and let's just pick up some stuff we
could press b and we could place this in
our
bag and you can notice an issue here
that the icons are going
behind the
bag i'll solve that in just a second
um but now when we go over to a chest
and press e and we can press b and we
can bring up our bag and place them
in to the chest
press escape and it will close both
panels so now you've got your bag
and the chest inventory are all separate
panels and then to fix the um inventory
ui controller with the player imagery
being behind it so to do that let's um
come to our canvas and let's just apply
all of our changes that we've just done
and then let's try and drag the mouse
object below player inventory it'll ask
to open up the prefab and then we just
need to make sure this is at the bottom
of the ui inventory controller window
because anything that's at the bottom
renders on top of the stuff above it
which i've never really liked i wish
stuff at the top would render above it's
a bit more kind of like photoshop them
with different layers
you can see that if we go over our
backpack
if we go over pick up some items
pick up an item and now it's rendering
on top of our backpack our swords in and
then we can come over here to these
chests and then we can pop some stuff
into the chests
and also as a sneak peek i've just
finished recording all of the shop
tutorial stuff so that is coming up in
the future just as a little little sneak
peek i'm actually working from like
episode 15 of the inventory tutorial
series which includes these shops that's
just a little sneak peek
um yeah i hope that solves your issue
if you've been having that issue um i
can't remember if i addressed this in a
future video never do just skip past
that bit thanks for watching bye
you